Guide to the UH Oral History Transcripts and Recordings
University of Houston Libraries
UH Oral History Transcripts and Recordings
1978-1981
1981-002
Phi Kappa Phi
0.75 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The collection contains the transcripts and cassettes of the Phi Kappa Phi oral history interviews. A small amount of written material and three computer diskettes are also included with the collection. All materials date from 1978 to 1985. The cassettes have been boxed separately for preservation reasons.
Historical Note:
During 1978 and 1979 Phi Kappa Phi undertook an oral history project to create a “Living History Library.” Manuscript librarian, David Robrock performed the interviews with former university administrators in an attempt to preserve a portion of the institution’s history. Robrock recorded conversations with Leta Hayden Gilbert (former administrative assistant to five UH Presidents), Charles F. Hiller, Walter W. Kemmerer (former President), C. F. McElhinney (former Business Manager and Vice-president), and Ruth S. Wikoff (UH’s first university librarian).
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston
Genre/Form of Material:
Audiotapes; Sound recordings
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the transcripts and cassettes of the Phi Kappa Phi oral history interviews. A small amount of written material and three computer diskettes are also included with the collection. All materials date from 1978 to 1985. The cassettes have been boxed separately for preservation reasons.
Detailed List of Contents
- Inventory
  - Project Inventory, January 20, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, June 20, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - UH Central “Leta Hayden Gilbert”, February 9, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Leta Hayden Gilbert - transcript (tape 1), September 13, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Leta Hayden Gilbert – transcript (tape 2), September 13, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Leta Hayden Gilbert and Ruth Wikoff - diskette, September 13, 1979, March 13, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charles F. Hiller - transcript, July 20, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Charles F. Hiller - transcript (copy 2), July 20, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charles F. Hiller - transcript, October 10, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Charles F. Hiller - transcript (copy 2), October 10, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charles F. Hiller - diskette, July 20, 1978, October 10, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Charles F. Hiller - transcript, December 11, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Charles F. Hiller - diskette, December 11, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Walter W. Kemmerer - transcript, June 6, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Walter W. Kemmerer - transcript (copy 2), June 6, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Charles F. McElhinney - transcript, July 13, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ruth Wikoff - transcript, March 13, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cassettes
  - Leta Hayden Gilbert - tape 1, September 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 1)
  - Leta Hayden Gilbert - tape 2, September 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 2)
  - Charles F. Hiller - tape 1, July 20, 1978 (Box 2, Audiotape 3)
  - Charles F. Hiller - tape 2, October 10, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 4)
  - Charles F. Hiller - tape 3, December 11, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 5)
  - Charles F. Hiller - tape 4, December 11, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 6)
  - W. W. Kemmerer - tape 1, June 6, 1978 (Box 2, Audiotape 7)
  - W. W. Kemmerer - tape 2, June 6, 1978 (Box 2, Audiotape 8)
  - C. F. McElhinney, July 13, 1978 (Box 2, Audiotape 9)
  - Ruth Wikoff, March 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 10)
  - Leta Hayden Gilbert - tape 1 (copy 2), September 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 11)
  - Leta Hayden Gilbert - tape 2 (copy 2), September 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 12)
  - Charles F. Hiller - tape 3 and 4 (copy 2), December 11, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 13)
  - Ruth Wikoff (copy 2), March 13, 1979 (Box 2, Audiotape 14)